《越狱》前情提要K
Previously on Prison Break:
那些浑蛋死了 都比你我活着要值钱
Those ass-hats are worth more dead than you and I are alive.
有人一定会拿到赏金 还不如由我来拿
Somebody's gonna get that money. Might be me.
这种工作 如果多个帮手会顺利许多
A job like that might go a little smoother with an extra pair of hands.
派潜水员到河里打捞
I want divers down in the river.
-史考特寇布雷纳吗？ -你一定是黛伯拉珍
- Are you Scott Kolbrenner? - You must be Debra Jean,
-很高兴认识你 -我也是
- It's nice to meet you. - Same here.
费朋纳兹又打算出面了
Apparently, Fibonacci's coming up for air again.
如果他出席听证会作证 很多人都会遭殃
And if he testifies at that hearing, a lot of people are going down.
卡洛琳，警察把她带走了 我当然会盯好她
Caroline, they're taking her in. Of course. I'll keep an eye on her.
大家好，我是莎拉 我有毒瘾
Hi, my name is sara and I'm an addict.
-大家好，我是兰斯，我有毒瘾 -你好，兰斯
- Hi, my name is Lance and I'm an addict. - Hi, Lance.
-辛苦你了，医生 -你现在可以走了
- You did one hell of a job, doc. - It's okay for you to leave now.
我会走的，但是你不能走
Oh, I'm leaving, you're not.
-目的地是哪里，先生？ -犹他州
- Where to, sir? - Utah.
-准备好了吗？ -好了
- Ready? - Yeah.
-是哥哥还是弟弟？ -可能是史柯菲
- So which one of them was it? - Might be scofield.
我看他哥哥的尸体 也在里面吧
Probably gonna find his brother in there too.
你会和她见面吗？
Are you meeting up with her?
-那个医生？ -我不知道
- Your doctor? - I don't know.
我就知道，跟着那贱人 就能找到他们
I knew the little whore would take us right to them.
你们到墨西哥之后有何打算？ 你们要去哪里？
What happens when you get to Mexico? Where will you go?
你不知道会比较好 对大家都好
It's best if you don't know. It's best for everyone.
到下个城镇会让你下车 我答应给的一万美金会汇给你
We'll drop you off in the next town, and I'll wire you that 10,000, like I said.
应该不会超过一两周
Shouldn't take more than a week or two.
麦可，有人跟来了
Michael, we got company.
这辆车想做什么？
What the hell's he doing?
-抓紧！抓紧！ -抓紧！
- Hold on! Hold on! - Hold on!
他们是谁？
Who is it?
是谁？
是贝里克
It's Bellick.
抓紧！
Hold on!
抓紧！抓紧！
Hold on, hold on.
-快趴下！快趴下！ -抓紧！抓紧！
- Duck! Down! - Hold on, hold on.
抓好！
Hold on.
车还能再快一点吗？
Can this thing go any faster?
你觉得呢？
What do you think?
小心！
Look out!
大家坐稳！
Hold on!
-小心！小心！ -抓好！
- Look out! Look out! - Hold on!
大家不许动！
Nobody move!
不准动！
很高兴又见到你们，两位
Oh, good to see you again, boy.
没必要搞到 有人受伤，长官
No need for anyone to get hurt, boss.
长官？到外面不必见外，水槽
Boss? Oh, there's no need for formalities anymore there, sink.
我已经不是公仆了 都要感谢你
I'm no longer an employee of the state, thanks to you.
我看有人想要领赏金
I think somebody wants that reward.
我们要的不是赏金，朋友
Oh, it's not about reward money, friend.
你的朋友曼杰告诉我们 你要去挖K
Your pal Manche told me all about your little treasure hunt...
威莫兰藏的宝藏
...for Westmoreland's stash.
上车吧
Get in the car.
我们要去犹他州
We're going to Utah.
片名：越狱风云
剧名：一人落网
警察全国上下跟着你们
Cops following you all over the country...
浑然不知其实只要跟着 跟住你们的人
...when all they had to do was tail the tail, you know.
快点，亲爱的
Move that moneymaker, sweetheart.
动作快，犯人
Let's move it, convict.
如果你知道犹他州宝藏的事 为何还需要我们？
If you know about the money in Utah, why do you need us?
在你们忙着逃亡时 曼杰没听清楚威莫兰所有的话
In the excitement of the escape, Manche didn't hear everything Westmoreland said...
那老头就撒手归西 不过听到的也够了
...before he kicked the bucket, but he heard enough.
犹他州、五百万 剩下的自己填空吧
Utah and five million. You'll fill in the blanks.
-你干嘛！ -别想轻举妄动
- Hey! - Don't even think about getting cute.
你们两兄弟要带我找到钱
You and your brother are gonna take me to where that money is...
否则这小贱人马上就会没命
...or the whore gets dead real fast.
你想我会是在吹牛吗？
Ask me if I'm bluffing.
（奥斯卡席尔斯）
在史柯菲公寓 下方的河有斩获
The dredging of the river beneath scofield's apartment bore some fruit.
在河床底下找到一个硬碟
Found a hard drive under the riverbed.
序号符合他入狱几个月前K
Serial numbers match an order that scofield put in with Dell...
（虽已定罪 迪比库柏却成传奇）
...a few months before he was incarcerated.
向戴尔下的一笔订单
他们已还原 约百分之十二的资料
They've recovered about 12 percent of the data so far.
（州长女儿获颁人道奖）
这又有何帮助？
And this is helping us how?
血液检验出炉了 意外现场都是阴性B型血
Blood tests came back. B negative all over that crash site.
-史柯菲与柏劳都是K -阴性B型，我知道
- Scofield and Burrows are... - B negative, I know.
-我去通知媒体 -不要
- I'll reach out to the media. - How about don't?
如果风声走漏K
If it gets out that the guy...
说计划的策划人可能已经死了K
...who masterminded this whole thing is possibly dead...
其他六名逃犯就会更谨慎
...the other six cons are gonna get their guards up more.
我们规定K各位注意
It is our policy... Excuse me.
规定是要确认之后 才能公布死讯
It is our policy not to announce deaths until they're confirmed.
车辆已经爆炸 加上血型吻合
We found an exploding car and a blood match.
-那就再做检验 -检验什么？
- Well, then do more tests. - On what?
保险杆，随便 我不在乎，拖延就对了
On the bumper. I don't know, I don't care. Just delay.
我要那些逃犯感到自满 而不是更谨慎
I want those guys out there getting more complacent, not more careful.
但伊朗政府承诺 加速该国核能计划
But the Iranian government promises to forge ahead with its nuclear program,
全国新闻方面，伊利诺州K
In national news, the eight escaped convicts,,,
福克斯河监狱的 八名逃犯依然在K
,,, from Fox River Penitentiary in Illinois are still at la...
我正在听新闻
I was listening to that.
-可是我想听这首歌 -真的？你喜欢约翰丹佛？
- Yeah, I wanna hear this. - Really? You like John Denver?
对
Yeah.
-你千万别当歌手 -什么？
- Don't quit your day job. - What?
我要喝点龙舌兰酒 才能真正展现歌喉
No, I just need a little tequila to get my karaoke on.
好吧
Yeah.
开慢一点
Hey, yo, slow down.
-时速只有六十五里而已K -开慢一点
- We're doing, like, 65 in a 60... - Yo, slow down.
好啦，老爸
All right, Dad.
最好不要被开罚单 罚金可是要两百块
You know, we can't be having that, man. Tickets are, like, 200 bones.
对
Yeah.
史柯菲 我没想过我会这么说
I never thought I'd say this, scofield...
我感谢上帝 让你来到福克斯河监狱
...but I thank God for the day you walked into Fox River.
还要感谢你越狱
And out of it.
不会有事的
It's gonna be okay.
我现在不想听你说话 你说过不会有事的
I don't wanna hear from you right now. You told me nothing would happen.
你答应过我的
You promised me.
史柯菲 那位小姐的火气真不小
Oh, that's one pissed off commie you got on your hands there, scofield.
你妈没教你对女人要有礼貌吗？ 还是她和她一样是妓女？
Didn't your mama tell you how to treat a lady, or was she a whore like this one?
-林克 -有问题吗，柏劳？
- Linc. - Got a problem there, Burrows?
我们只需要 你们其中一人去找钱
We only need one of you to take us to the money.
不要忘了
Remember that.
我们走
Let's go, buddy.
走吧
Let's go.
我在婚礼致词时喝得烂醉
I'd been really drunk at the wedding speech...
这是我们自那次之后 第一次说话
...and this was the first time that we'd spoken since then.
我感到自醒 真的让我觉悟
And it was cleansing. It was really cleansing.
谢谢各位
Thank you.
感谢你的分享，罗夫
Good share, Ralph.
时间已经到了 还有人想分享吗？
Well, we're out of time, unless there are any burning desires...
我有话要说K
Actually, I'd like to...
-如果还有时间的话 -请说
...you know, if there's time. - Of course.
我是兰斯，我有毒瘾
I'm Lance, and I'm an addict.
-你好，兰斯 -你好，兰斯
- Hi, Lance. - Hi, Lance.
我的母亲 上周死于多发性硬化症
My mother died of Ms last week.
她就这样走了
She just gave out.
就像我的祖父和姐姐一样
Just like my grandfather did, just like my sister did...
就像我K
...just like I...
我可以说句话吗？
If I may?
-多发性硬化症不是遗传疾病 -真的？你是医生吗？
- Ms isn't usually considered genetic. - Really? What are you, a doctor?
对K我是医生
I am, actually.
抱歉
Sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
（纽约，布鲁克林）
所有人面对墙壁 不准转头
All right, everybody, face the wall and look straight ahead.
眼睛往前看
Eyes front.
-搭机过程还好吗？ -很不平稳，东西都办妥了吗？
- How was your flight? - Bumpy. Everything's ready?
海军造船厂有一艘货柜船 船长是我们的人
We got a container ship down at the navy yard. Captain's one of ours.
他用货柜之名准备了一个包厢
He's got a stateroom listed as a cargo hold on the manifest.
让你和你家人上船 明天就会出海
You and your family will be on it when it sets sail tomorrow.
约翰，六天后 你们就会到达萨丁尼亚岛
Six days from now, John, you'll be in sardinia.
做得很好
Good work.
席哩亚
Sylvia.
爸
Dad.
是啊
Yeah.
我们好想念你
We missed you.
是啊
Yes.
我也想念你们
I missed you too.
都没事了，没事了
It's over, it's over.
（内布拉斯加州，夫连德）
快点
Come on.
快恢复知觉K
Come on, come on.
你在搞什么？
What the hell are you doing?
不关你的事
Mind your own business.
哪里有人车上会不放备胎的？
What kind of son of a bitch doesn't have a spare tire in his car?
因为备胎之前被用掉了
The kind that already used it.
那你这个倒霉鬼 就走回镇上买新的回来
Well, then you're just the sad sack that has to go back into town and get a new one.
有三里远
That's like three miles.
没错
That's right.
大家下车
All right, everybody out.
往那边走，快点
That way. Go on.
-小心走 -不要碰我
- Careful. - Don't touch me.
放轻松点
Just relax.
你说的话我都相信 你要我做的事我都照做
You know, I believed everything you told me, and I did everything you asked.
我为你冒生命危险
I risked my life for you.
我就为了一万块钱 拿生命当赌注？
For what? For $ 10,000 I risked my life?
竟然从头到尾 都有五百万等着你
And this entire time you've had $5 million just waiting there.
你是个浑蛋，麦可
You're a bastard, Michael.
要受这种气 希望你已经和她上过几次床了
For all that aggravation, I hope you get to hit that a few times, scofield.
进去那间小木屋等
We're gonna wait it out in that shack.
继续走，快点
Just keep moving. Come on.
进去，进去
Come on, come on.
小妞，继续走
Fantasia, get going.
我有事要私下跟你谈
I need to talk to you alone.
-你要做什么？ -像他毁掉我的人生一样回敬他
- What do you want? - To ruin his life like he's ruined mine.
-你看到什么，先生？ -引擎过热，所以我停下车
- And what did you see, sir? - I was overheating, so I pulled in.
这辆车已经停在这里了
This car was already here.
-你看到什么？ -我在看报纸，什么也没看到
- What about you? - Oh, I was reading. I didn't see nothing.
老兄！
Hey, buddy!
你是从哪里来的？
Where you coming from?
我？我只是去上厕所，大哥
Me? I was just hitting the head, boss.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
克莱
Clyde.
-克莱梅 -你有带证件吗，梅先生？
- Clyde May. - You got any ID, Mr. May?
我已经不开车了 所以没有什么证件
I don't drive anymore, so I don't really have any ID per se.
我在坎达哈的时候 中东佬在我的吉普车下放了炸弹
Camel jockey left a big box of boom-boom under my jeep back in Kandahar.
-你是军人？ -曾经是
- You military? - Was.
-你的车子在哪里？ -就是我的一双腿
- Which one's your vehicle? - These two sleds right here.
不过其余时间我都搭便车
That is, the in-between rides, anyhow.
你都搭便车，但行李可真少
Ain't much of a bag to be hitchhiking with.
我需要的东西不多
I travel light.
你在这种荒凉的地方到处走？
You're just hoofing it out here, middle of nowhere?
我至少有权利四处看看 我断手报效的国家吧？
I do have the right to see a little bit of the country I lost my hand for, don't I?
你到底有什么事，警官？
Why don't you tell me what this is about?
这里有一辆没有驾驶的车
We got a vehicle here without a driver.
目前只有你 是没有车子的驾驶
And at present, you're the only driver without a vehicle.
原来是这件事？ 你为何不早说？
Hell, is that what this is all about? Why didn't you say so?
厕所里有个浑小子在上大号
Dirty hippie kid dropping a deuce in the facilities.
他两分钟前才开那辆车过来
He came in with that car not two minutes ago.
进去看看
Check it out.
你是陆军吗？
What were you, Army?
不是，我是海军陆战队
Hell, no. Corps.
真的？永远忠诚，兄弟 哪个部队的？
Well, then, semper fi, brother. What outfit were you?
一九六小队
Hundred and ninety-sixth.
一九六小队？
Hundred and ninety-sixth?
我没听过 你们驻军在哪里？
Never heard of it. Where they out of?
小队长
Hey, sarge.
老兄，我什么也没做
Hell, man, I didn't do nothing.
他的背包里有钥匙 他却说他没有开车
Found these in his knapsack after he said he had no car.
什么？
What?
（警察）
永远忠诚，兄弟
Semper fi, brother.
永远忠诚
Semper fi.
不要紧张 那没什么帮助
Stop stressing. It doesn't do any good.
或许你该开始紧张 他们等着要杀死我们
Maybe you ought to start stressing if they're gonna put a bullet in our heads.
他们需要我们 只有我们能找到钱
They need us. They need us to get that money.
我真佩服你的乐观
I admire your optimism.
她会投靠他们 我有预感
She's rolling, man. I can feel it.
你想毁掉史柯菲？ 要他死的人多得是
So you wanna ruin scofield's life? Well, get in line.
你真正的目的是什么？
What are you really looking for?
-跟你一样，钱 -钱？你要钱？
- Same as you. Money. - Money? You want money?
给你一万如何？
Ten grand. How's that sound?
我们现在就来 躺在地板上做
We do it right now, right there on those floorboards.
你想得美
Not in a thousand years.
那就滚开 你对我没有用处
Beat it, then. You got nothing else I need.
典型的男人 我讲的是上百万的钱
Typical man. I'm talking about millions of dollars...
-你却为了性爱不要 -没错
...and you'd piss it away for sex. - That's right.
我原本希望麦可骗不了你
And I was hoping you wouldn't let Michael outsmart you too.
史柯菲骗不了任何人
Scofield ain't outsmarting no one.
你以为爆胎是意外吗？
You think that tire went flat by accident?
-你要怎么帮忙？ -我可以查出钱的地点
- What are you offering? - I can find out where the money is.
-他信任我 -你想要什么？
- He trusts me. - What do you want?
分我一份
My fair share.
你查出钱的地点 我就分给你二十万美金
You find out where that money is, your fair share is $200,000.
-总数有五百万，太少了K -枪在我手上，女孩
- Out of five million? That's not very... - I got the gun, girl.
我愿意和你合作 算你走运
You're lucky you're a partner at all.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
费朋纳兹在华盛顿特区
Fibonacci's in DC.
对，他在丹佛 亚特兰大、迈阿密K
Yeah, and he's in Denver, Atlanta, Miami.
-我知道 -不K这次是真的
- I know. - No, no, no. This time it's for real.
他又要出庭作证了
He's testifying again.
他现在就在华盛顿
He's in Washington right now.
环球旅馆 一一六号房
The Globe Hotel, room 116.
-消息来源正确吗？ -是从新泽西传来的
- Is this information any good? - It's from New Jersey.
鱼头汤米想向你致敬
Fishhead Tommy wants to pay tribute.
去准备车
Get the car.
约翰，看看你四周！
Look at this room, John.
你自己看！
Look.
我们一家人可以团圆
We can be a family again.
可是你不在乎我们去冒险 只为了报仇？
But you wanna risk it all, disrespect us. And for what, for vengeance?
-他背叛我K -我不在乎
- He betrayed me... - I don't care.
他背叛了我们
He betrayed us.
我很抱歉 但你永远不会了解K
I'm sorry, you will never understand what happens...
被关进监狱有何感受
...when you're in prison.
可是你可能会被抓回监狱
But you could go back to prison.
我向天发誓
I swear to God...
我宁愿死也不要回监狱 我永远都不可能再回去
...I'd rather die than go back. There's no going back. Never, ever again.
耶稣救了你一命，约翰 不要背弃他
Christ saved you, John. Don't turn your back on him.
不要背弃我们
Don't turn your back on us.
我K
I...
我不知道 离甘尼森二十里远吧
I don't know, about 20 miles from Gunnison.
他来了，我得挂电话了
He's coming. I have to go.
你跟谁说话？
Who was that?
没什么，只是我爸爸
Nobody. It's just my father.
-好 -听我说K
- All right. - Hey, listen.
我们在下个汽车旅馆过夜好吗？
Do you mind if we stop at the next motel?
-现在才下午四点 -对，可是已经开很久了
- It's only, like, 4:00. - Yeah, but we've been driving forever.
-没关系，我来开 -我真的很想休息
- That's cool, I'll drive. - I really just wanna stop.
-现在出发也许K -史考特
- But if we get on the road now... - scott.
这是我的车 我想要休息，可以吗？
It's my car, and I'm tired of being in it, okay?
好吧
All right.
我听说有人通风报信
Heard about the call coming in.
你相信吗？这么多人中 竟然是通报的人帮忙抓到第一个
Can you believe it? Of all the players, it's the rat that could give us our first collar.
你们如果想上厕所，就忍住
If you guys need to use the can, hold it.
美女，如果想上厕所 我愿意看着你，坐下
You need to tinkle, sweet pea, I'll watch you anytime. Sit down.
手放到背后
Hands behind your back.
你真花了不少时间
Took your time.
要取得男人的信任需要时间
It takes time to gain a man's confidence.
你说的对 我说什么他都相信
You're right, he'll bite on anything I say.
告诉我要把他困在哪里 我就告诉他钱在那边
You just tell me where we trap him, and I'll tell him that's where the money is.
你是加油站的那个人对吧？
Hey. You're the guy from the gas station, right?
我是那个车坏掉的人
I'm the guy who was having car trouble.
-现在车子恢复正常了？ -对，水帮浦坏了
- Seems to be purring along now, huh? - Yeah. Water pump.
害我花了两百块买新的
Two hundred bucks for this heap.
坏了的确是麻烦
They'll get you.
对了，我不想多管闲事K
Look, I hope I'm not out of line...
但我听到你和警察 谈到你的手伤
...but I heard you telling the cop back there about your hand.
我小时候父亲在越南战死
My old man was killed in Nam when I was a kid...
所以我对军人相当尊敬
...so I have the utmost respect for our servicemen.
我只是替国家效命
Just serving my country.
很多人都很感激你们 如果你需要搭便车的话K
A lot of us are grateful for it. Listen, if you need a ride or something...
老实说我的K 我的腿的确酸了
Well, to be honest with you, my dogs are kind of barking.
太好了
Well, all right.
我是杰瑞克庭
Jerry Curtin.
我是克莱，克莱梅
Clyde. Clyde May.
我的小孩丹妮坐在前座 希望你不介意坐后座
My kid Danny is riding shotgun. I hope you don't mind sitting in the back.
你好，我是丹妮尔
Hi. I'm Danielle.
你好啊
Hi, yourself.
-你在吗？ -你要做什么？
- Hey. - What do you want?
-我要上厕所 -又要上？
- I need to use the bathroom. - Again?
我的膀胱很小
I have a small bladder.
不只如此吧
That ain't all you got.
站起来
Get up.
如何？
Well?
他们打算抓住你 那个哥哥在犹他州有朋友
They plan to trap you. The big one, he's got friends in Utah.
狐群狗党，地方叫潘圭奇
Criminals. A town called Panguitch.
他的朋友在农场种毒品
They grow drugs on a farm there.
他们会告诉你钱在那里 但其实不然
They'll tell you that's where the money is, but no money.
只有朋友带着枪等着你
Just old friends with guns, waiting for you.
这好解决 不要去潘圭奇就好
Easy enough. We take a pass on Panguitch.
-钱真正的埋藏地点在哪里？ -我马上就能查出来
- Where's the money really? - I'll find out soon enough.
可是这资讯 不只二十万美金
But 200,000 was old price for this information.
-开个新价钱给我 -你想要再交涉
- I want a new price. - She's trying to renegotiate.
要不是我 你会死在大麻农场
If it wasn't for me, you'd be face-down in a marijuana farm.
三分之一
One third.
如果你要一百六十万 就不能只给我资讯，美女
It's gonna take a lot more than information if you want a million-six, sweet pea.
-你要什么？ -你很清楚
- Such as? - You know.
-让我随时能尝尝甜头 -就这样？
- Piece of that can, anytime I want it. - Is that it?
你不打算赏我巴掌吗？
Aren't you gonna slap me?
我和比你更不值钱的男人 上过床，相信我
I've slept with men for a lot less, trust me.
“你想得美” 这态度到哪儿去了？
What happened to "Never in a thousand years"?
那是交涉手段
That was negotiating.
那么K
So...
一言为定？
...deal?
一言为定
Deal.
我们手头上 有十五万块钱，约翰
We got 150,000 here, John.
加上维托利欧在索拉诺斯的房子 我们可以靠利息过生活
With Vittorio's place in solanos, we'll be able to live off the interest.
你们的父亲在哪里？
Where's your father?
（华盛顿特区北方 九十五号州际公路）
Everything all right, boss?
你没事吧，老大？
没事，尽快完成这件事
Yeah. Let's get this over with...
我才能和家人团聚
...so I can get back to my family.
她会成功的
She'll get it done.
妮卡和我的牵扯太深了
Nika and I have come too far together.
-只要牵扯到钱，就不能信任 -有时不得不信
- When money's on the line, trust no one. - Sometimes you have to.
如果想活命就不能相信
Not if you wanna survive, you don't.
你真的不相信任何人对吧？
You really don't trust anyone, do you?
经过这些遭遇 你能怪我吗？
Can you blame me after all that's happened?
不，我是指之前 你入狱之前
No, I mean before that. Before prison.
我只要信任他人就会被伤害
Every time I trusted someone I got burned.
只要接近他人就会被害惨
Every time I got close to someone, I got screwed.
这种事我最清楚 你也该清楚点
I know better and so should you.
对，莲花汽车旅馆
That's right, the Lotus Motel,
（汽车旅馆）
I don't know the number. I can't talk anymore, I have to go.
我不知道电话 我不能说了，我要挂电话了
对了，我这么问 有点放肆，不过K
Well, check it, I know this might be a little forward and all, but...
我有事想问你
Let me ask you something.
你有男人吗？
You got a man?
我是说男朋友？
I mean, a boyfriend?
-我在说什么，摩门教徒一定K -我不是摩门教徒
- No, what am I thinking? You're Mormon... - I'm not Mormon.
你认为犹他州的女孩 都是摩门教徒？
You think all girls from Utah are Mormons?
不是吗？
They are, aren't they?
等等，那你就可以享乐，对吧？
Well, yo. Hey, then you can party, right? Hey.
派十二名持枪探员等我降落
When I land, I want 12 armed agents waiting for me on the ground.
通知他们，我要从机场 直接前往汽车旅馆
Tell them I wanna go to the motel from the airstrip.
知道了
You got it.
我之前态度不佳 我向你道歉
I was an ass before. I apologize.
的确不太好
A little bit.
抱歉，拿去吧
Sorry. Here you go.
我是大浑蛋，我道歉
I was a huge ass. I apologize.
这点我不跟你争辩
I'm not gonna argue with you.
我怎么会料到有医生在场？
Well, what are the odds that you're actually a doctor?
的确有道理 糟糕的医生才会来这里，不过K
Fair enough. They're probably not good, but...
我不该打断你 我很抱歉
And I should not have interrupted you, and I'm sorry.
-我也很抱歉 -好，我接受你的道歉
- I'm sorry too. - Well, then, apologies accepted.
蓝莓派很好吃
I recommend the blueberry pie.
那我就吃蓝莓派
Blueberry pie it is.
（汽车旅馆）
-你好，丹妮 -你好
- Hey there, Danny. - Hey.
你爸真仁慈 帮我出过夜的房钱
Sure was nice of your daddy to buy me a room for the night.
对，他一向喜欢帮助退伍军人
Yeah, he's always helping out with vets and stuff.
是啊
Yeah.
他是个好人
Good man.
不过如果能继续前往犹他州 就太好了
But I was wishing we could've kept going on toward Utah.
现在时间还早 路途也还很遥远
Lots of light left in the day, lots of road to go.
只要我爸背痛 就会停下来休息
When Dad's back acts up we stop.
《年轻女孩》？
"Young Miss"?
这种东西不是给你看的吧
That's kind of insulting, isn't it?
你可是亭亭玉立的女人
I mean, you're a grown woman.
但大人都会把 你这年纪的女孩当成小孩
But adults are always trying to infantilize girls your age.
把你当小孩看管
Treat you like children.
对啊，我爸不让我戴耳环 我已经十四岁了
No duh. My dad won't let me get earrings, and I'm 14.
我就是这个意思
You see, that's what I'm saying.
你已经有能力可以 自己做决定
You are more than perfectly capable of making your own decisions.
-去跟我爸说吧 -不过他听不进去，对吧？
- Tell my dad that. - Yeah, but he don't wanna hear it, right?
因为他希望 你永远是个小婴儿
Because he wants to keep you as a baby.
对吧？即使你已经长大 可以选择K
Right? Even though you're more than old enough to choose...
穿什么衣服K
...how you wanna dress...
戴什么首饰
...or accessorize.
-你在做什么？ -只是跟你做朋友
- What are you doing? - In need of a friend...
-不行，我要告诉我爸 -我不擅长跟孩子K
- No, no. I'm telling my dad. - You know, I'm not good at kid...
等等！
Wait!
她会错意了
She's got it all wrong.
到外面等
Wait outside.
你和我得摆平这件事
You and I are gonna work this out.
杰瑞，劝你最好别这么做
Jerry, you really don't want to do this.
你的坚定意志令人激赏
The thing I like about you is your determination.
我的家人在克拉德诺 等着我K
I have a family in Kladno that have been waiting for me...
接他们过来
...to send for them.
他们知道你从事哪一行吗？
They know what kind of work you're in?
他们以为我在咖啡店打工
They think I work at starbucks.
你真的以为我很蠢吗？
How stupid do you think I am?
我爸总是说 骗我一次，是你不好
My daddy always said, "Fool me once, shame on you...
骗我两次 我就把你打倒在地
...fool me twice, and I put you in the ground."
再耍花招 我就杀了这妓女，懂了吗？
Any more games and I stop the whore's air, understand?
感谢你的艳舞，美女
Thanks for the dance, sweet pea.
贱人
You bitch.
骗到你了
Fooled you.
我扛轮胎来了 叫那些犯人换轮胎
I carried it. The cons can change it.
贝里克 你真的很无能，你知道吗？
Oh, you really suck, Bellick, you know that?
绑住他，来吧
Roll him. Let's go.
手放到背后
Hands behind your back.
谢谢
Thank you.
你和监狱医生一样傻 你知道吗？
You're as stupid as the prison doc, you know that?
-别理他 -她也被他骗了
- Ignore him. - He conned her too.
她以为他爱她 结果得到什么？
Made her think he loved her. Look what she got.
用药过量 还可能被判刑三十年
An overdose and a shot at 30 years inside.
你在胡说什么？
What are you talking about?
看来你最近没看报纸，大学生
You haven't been reading the papers, have you, college boy?
警察发现你的女友 被自己的呕吐噎到面色惨白
Cops found your girlfriend fish-belly white, gargling her own puke.
-闭嘴 -反正你也不在乎
- Shut up. - What do you care?
-只要她替你开门 -闭嘴！
- As long as she left the door open for you. - Shut up!
说到痛处了是吗？
Hit a sore spot, didn't I?
（汽车旅馆 游泳池/电视/运动台）
爸？
Dad?
这真是我吃过最美味的派
It really is, like, the best pie I ever had.
但你知道 加点什么会更好吗？
Do you know what it needs, though?
一些可卡因
Some crack.
不用很多，一小撮就好
No, I mean, you know, not a lot. A pinch.
-一撮可卡因？ -一撮可卡因
- A pinch of crack? - A pinch of crack.
一撮可卡因、一小块海洛因
A pinch of crack, a dollop of smack.
-这才是最棒的派 -你真是够了
- That's good pie. - That's so wrong.
不好吗？
No?
好吧
Okay.
-你好 -莎拉K是我
- Hello? - Sara, It's me,
你想干什么？
What do you want?
我没时间多说
I don't have time to talk.
警方很可能正在监听
There's every chance they're listening to this call right now.
可是我有好多话想说
But there's a lot I want to say,
求求你不要挂掉电话
Please don't hang up on me.
-我K不想和你说话 -我听说K
- I don't wanna talk to you. - I heard about...
我听说你的事了
I heard about what happened.
我想让你知道K
I want you to know...
我想让你知道我有多抱歉
I want you to know how sorry I am. For everything.
抱歉对我现在遇到的麻烦 一点帮助也没有
Sorry's not gonna do me a whole lot of good with what I'm up against right now.
听着
Listen,
所有与我和我哥 有关的人都有危险
Anyone with any ties to me and my brother is in danger now.
我和你跟你哥 已经没有关系了
I have no ties to you and your brother anymore.
我有办法保护你
There is a way I can protect you.
办法已经在你手上
It's already in your possession.
-你在胡说什么？ -是真的，莎拉，你和我的K
- What are you talking about? - It was real, sara, you and me.
感情是真的
It's real.
麦可？
Michael?
-到旅馆还要多久？ -预计十分钟，长官
- How long to the motel? - Approximately 10 minutes, sir.
缩短到五分钟
Let's make it five.
我已经好久没好好洗个澡了
Yo, I haven't taken a shower like that in forever.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
-我本来要给你个惊喜 -什么惊喜？
- I was gonna surprise you. - Surprise me how?
我要去买龙舌兰莱姆酒
I was gonna get some tequila and limes.
-好，等我一下K -不用，我马上回来
- All right, well, hold up. I'Il... - No, no, no. It'll only take a minute.
你留在这里休息就好
Stay here and relax.
你看起来有点紧张
You seem kind of nervous.
-是吗？ -对，你在冒汗
- I do? - Yeah, you're sweating.
也许我真的有点紧张
Well, maybe I am nervous.
相信我 你什么都不必担心，好吗？
Trust me, girl, you got nothing to worry about, all right?
-我是好人 -你看起来是好人
- I'm one of the good guys. - You seem like it.
（全球汽车旅馆）
别轻举妄动
Hang on tight.
-我已经叫经理打开门了 -知道了
- I had the manager unlock the door. - Got it.
约翰，如果你要找陷害你的人
If you're looking for the rat, John...
费朋纳兹在两千里之外
...Fibonacci's 2000 miles from here.
你是谁？
Who are you?
当地警察，还是调查局？
Local cops or feds?
联邦调查局 抓你这种身份的人需要精英
Feds, John. Only roll out the best for a man of your stature.
我有权知道是谁陷害我
I deserve to know who turned on me.
-是汤米吗？ -他违反诈骗腐败组织集团犯罪法
- Tommy? - The man was facing a RICo rap.
他不想坐牢
He did not want to go to prison.
你应该能体谅他
I'm sure you can appreciate that...
因为你了解坐牢的痛苦
...knowing what you know about the place now.
约翰，不管你心中有何打算 别那么做
Whatever you're thinking about doing, John, don't.
你今天不回福克斯河监狱 就是去停尸间
You are going back to Fox River today, or the morgue.
你自己决定
That's your call.
我要出来了
I'm coming out.
先把武器亮出来，约翰
Weapons come out first, John.
请原谅我
Forgive me.
好，我要出来了
Yeah, I'm coming out.
慢慢来，约翰 慢慢来
Easy, John. Easy.
-他的右手有武器！ -他们是认真的警员
- He's got a weapon. Right hand. - These are serious men here.
被要求一有攻击迹象 就要开枪
They have instructions to shoot at the first sign of aggression.
拜托，请你不要这样
Please, I'm asking you respectfully.
放下武器 跪下，双手放在头上
Drop the weapon, kneel, and put your hands on your head.
我只在上帝面前下跪
I kneel only to God.
他并没有出现
I don't see him here.
不！
No!
我想我搞砸了
I think I screwed up,
我爸是空军将军 控制狂一个
My dad's an Air Force colonel. Total Nazi.
他是那种过度保护的恐怖父亲
One of those nightmare, overprotective dads.
-然后呢？ -我打电话给他
- Yeah? - Well, I called him.
告诉他我和你一起上路
Told him I was traveling with you.
还说我们住在 同一间旅馆房间
Told him that we were staying in the same hotel room.
-小姐K -怎么了？
- Girl. - What?
你得学习说谎 你在想什么？
You gotta learn how to lie. What were you thinking?
对K不知为何 我就是无法说谎
I don't know... Yeah, for some reason I don't know how.
我告诉他我和男生 同住一间房间，他已经很生气了
He was mad enough when I told him I was staying in a hotel room with a guy.
-还不只如此 -是啊K
- That was one thing. - Yeah, yeah.
当我说和我过夜的男生
When I told him I was staying in a hotel...
我有点喜欢 他就完全失控了
...with a guy that I maybe sort of liked, he lost it.
等等K你说什么？
Wait. Wait, what?
你不介意吧？
Is that okay?
至少让我们载你到镇上
At least let us take you into town.
不用，要是被人看见 跟你们一起，我就麻烦大了
No. If I'm seen with you it's a lot of trouble for me.
我可以用走的 只有一里远
I can walk. It's only a mile.
多亏你的帮忙 我们才能逃到这里
We never would've made it this far without you.
现在你们要离开我 跨越边境了
But now you're crossing the border without me.
你不能去我们要去的地方
You can't go where we're going.
那种生活不适合你
It's not a life for you.
那么就这样了
Then that's it, then.
我们永别了
It's over for good.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你要小心点
Be safe.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
我爱过你，麦可
I loved you, Michael.
我以为你也会爱我 但是你只是在利用我
And I thought I was gonna get that back, but you just used me.
-不是这样的 -你不该这么对我
- That's not true. - I deserve more than this.
我不应该只是 你需要帮助时才来找的女孩
I deserve more than just being the girl that you call when you need something.
你真的以为 可以找到犹他州的钱？
You think you're gonna find the money in Utah?
我不在乎犹他州的钱！
I don't care about the money in Utah.
我不想再犯罪了
I don't want any more crime.
把你们交给警察 我可以拿到二十万，合法的钱
I turn you in, I get $200,000. Legal money.
我要把你们交给警察
You're the policeman's problem now.
-妮卡K -不要靠近我，否则我会开枪
- Nika. - Don't come any closer or I'll shoot you.
你不会开枪的
No, you won't.
祝你好运
Good luck to you.
-你好 -你好
- Hey. - Hey.
总部问你 亚布兹走进房间前
HQ called. They're asking why you didn't intercept Abruzzi...
为何不先拦截他？
...when he was walking towards the motel.
他是个黑帮老大 把他困住是最佳的方式
The man was a mob boss. The right move was to get him trapped.
他们说依照你的方式 只会有一种结果
They're saying the way you played it, there was only one possible outcome.
如果总部对我的方式有意见 欢迎下次拿枪和我一起出勤
HQ has a problem with the way I do it, they can pick a gun and follow me next time.
（黑帮老大亚布兹 被判终身监禁）
Scofield always knew the rat was the key to Abruzzi.
史柯菲知道 叛徒是亚布兹的弱点
我们只是放出诱饵 让亚布兹上勾
We just put it out on the wire and Abruzzi bit.
说到史柯菲
Speaking of scofield...
车子爆炸是假的
...the crash was staged.
是猪血
Pig blood.
聪明的小子
Smart kid.
（奥斯卡席尔斯）
这么聪明 问题就在于迟早K
The problem with being that clever, is that sooner or later...
他会聪明反被聪明误
...you end up getting too clever for your own good.
晚安
Good night.
我一定会让你吃尽苦头
You have no idea what you're in for.